Guide to the Starrett family papers, 1790-1933.
Starrett family papers, 1790-1933
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Starrett family papers, 1790-1933.
142
Starrett family.
575 pieces.
Personal and business papers and letters, including patent rights, wills, notes, bills and receipts, land deed, school lists, land surveys, Civil War and War of 1812 material, indentures, account books, almanac, newspapers, broadsides, maps, material on local Democratic politics, items on estate management, recipes, and formulas.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Starrett family lived in Ovid, Seneca County, N.Y.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and business papers and letters, including patent rights, wills, notes, bills and receipts, land deed, school lists, land surveys, Civil War and War of 1812 material, indentures, account books, almanac, newspapers, broadsides, maps, material on local Democratic politics, items on estate management, recipes, and formulas.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Starrett family.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Seneca County.
Places:
Ovid (N.Y.)--History.; Seneca County (N.Y.)--History, Local.; United States--History--War of 1812.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Seneca County (N.Y.)--Politics and government.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Broadsides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters and business papers of Charles and Rachel Caywood Starrett, 1799-Oct. 9, 1839 (Box 1)
- School bill, 1826 (Box 1)
- Public auction papers of James Van Lieuw, 1832 (Box 1)
- Public auction papers of John Caywood, 1834 (Box 1)
- Fire Insurance policy, 1839 (Box 1)
- Letters and papers concerning Mrs. Hallett (Box 1)
- Letters and business papers of Charles Starrett, James Starrett, William Starrett, John Starrett, Joseph Covert, 1840-1900 (Box 1)
- List of properties (1842) of Charles Starrett, deceased (Box 1)
- Whig Almanac, 1844 (Box 1)
- Bee Hive Patent Rights, 1844 (Box 1)
- The Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad bank note for $5.00, 1853 (Box 1)
- Fire Insurance policy, 1854 (Box 1)
- Letters, 1863-1865: Rachel Starrett's letters home while visiting her sister in New York City in 1863 - a little about the Draft Riots; letters from Sarah "Aunt Sally" Pinkerton to her mother and sister at Starrett's Corners - many references to Lincoln, Civil War, Draft; letters from Charles Starrett to his mother Rachel Starrett - references to Civil War, Lincoln, and Western Lands (Charles Starrett was a dealer in Western Real Estate, hence the trips he describes.) (Box 1)
- New York Herald (copy), Apr. 16, 1865 - death of Lincoln (Box 1)
- Widow's Pension claim for War of 1812, 1874, Rachel Starrett (Box 1)
- George W. Eylenbergh drug store papers, 1882, Seneca County, Farmer Village (Mrs. Gage's father worked for Mr. Eylenbergh) (Box 1)
- White Sewing Maching sale agreements, 1886 (Box 1)
- J. J. Palmer & Co. sale agreements, 1894, for Japan Roofing Paint (Box 1)
- Pocket maps, shipper's guides - North Carolina and New York, 1900 (Box 1)
- Sheriff's notice, 1902, to William Starrett Covert (Box 2)
- Souvenir program "Old Home Week," 1906, Seneca County (Box 2)
- Programme - Centennial of Townsendville, 1810-1910 (Box 2)
- 17 booklets: Enrolled Votes, Electors, County and Town Officers - Seneca County, Covert, 1918-1933 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous undated:
  - Allentown Military Collegiate Academy poem and reward for merit to Willie Starrett (Box 2)
  - School bills (Box 2)
  - Survey land bills (Box 2)
  - Lamson Sperry Clock Regulating Directions (Box 2)
  - J. J. Palmer Elastic Japan Roofing Paint papers (Box 2)
  - Recipes, formulas, remedies (Box 2)
  - Broadsides and clippings (Box 2)
- 7 account books and work books, 1899-1912, 1 undated, all on shelves (Box 2)
- 1 land deed of Oliver Lozier signed by George Clinton, Governor of New York, Montgomery - Ovid, Lot 31, July 9, 1790 (Box 3)